servicechannel.com 2018-09-20

# Privacy Policy - ServiceChannel

We at **_ServiceChannel.com, Inc. and our affiliates_** (“ServiceChannel,” “we,” “us” or “our”) know that our users (“you” or “your”) care about how your personal information (referred to as ‘personal data’ in Europe) is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, and disclose information, and your rights in relation to that information. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy **.** By using the ServiceChannel mobile or web applications (collectively, the “App”) and any services, products, features, or content available on ServiceChannel’s websites, including without limitation, [www.servicechannel.com](http://www.servicechannel.com/), [www.fixxbook.com](http://www.fixxbook.com/), and [www.sendaguy.com](http://www.sendaguy.com/), (together with the App, the “Services”), you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy, and you hereby acknowledge that we will collect, use, and share your information in the following ways. You also acknowledge and agree that your use of any and all services, products, features, content or applications other than (or additional to) the Services offered by or for ServiceChannel may be governed by separate terms of service and privacy policies.

## Quick links

We recommend that you read this Privacy Policy in full to ensure you are fully informed.  However, if you only want to access a particular section of this Privacy Policy, then you can click on the relevant link below to jump to that section.

> I.  WHAT DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVER?
> 
> II. WHAT INFORMATION DOES SERVICECHANNEL COLLECT?
> 
> III.  USE AND SHARING OF INFORMATION
> 
> IV.  LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING PERSONAL INFORMATION
> 
> V.  INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS
> 
> IV.  WHAT RIGHTS AND CHOICES DO I HAVE?
> 
> VII.  DATA RETENTION
> 
> VIII.  MARKETING AND EMAIL COMMUNICATION
> 
> IX.  SECURITY
> 
> X.  CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
> 
> XI.  CONTACT US

**I. WHAT DOES THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVER?**

This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of Personal Information and Other Information we gather from you when you are accessing or using our Services. Personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) may include, but is not limited to, your name, username, home and/or work address, telephone number, e-mail address, company affiliation and associated interests. We collect some of this Personal Information by requesting it directly from you, and we may also obtain information about you from third-party sources, as described below.

ServiceChannel also observes, derives, collects and infers other information (“Other Information”) through your interaction with and use of the Services, which does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an individual. Other Information may include, but is not limited to, browser and device information (such as browser type and version, operating system and version, device ID and language, and Internet connection), data collected through automated electronic interactions, application usage data, demographic information, geographic location information ( e.g. country or city-level location) or geo-location information (including without limitation, precise geo-location), IP address, and statistical and aggregated information.  Other Information may constitute Personal Information when coupled with Personal Information that we hold and process about you.  In such circumstances such Other Information shall be treated as Personal Information.   

Collecting this information enables us to better understand the visitors who come to our Website, where they come from, and what content on our Website is of interest to them.  We use this information for our internal analytics purposes and to improve the quality and relevance of our Website to our visitors.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, or to individuals that we do not employ or manage.

Our Services are not intended for users under 13 years of age.  We do not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Information from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to access or use the Services or send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address.

We gather various types of Personal Information and Other Information from our users, as explained more fully below.  We may use this Personal Information and Other Information to personalize and improve our services, to allow our users to set up a user account and profile, to contact users, to fulfill your requests for certain products and services, to analyze how users utilize the Services, and as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. We may share certain types of Personal Information with third parties, as described below. ****

**II. WHAT INFORMATION DOES SERVICECHANNEL COLLECT?**

1\. Information You Provide to Us

We collect information you provide directly to us, such as when you create or modify your account and profile, request or provide services, contact customer support, or otherwise communicate with us. This information may include: name, email, phone number, postal address, profile picture, payment method, items and services requested, delivery and service notes, and other information you choose to provide. You can choose not to provide us with certain Personal Information, but then you may not be able to register with us or to take full advantage of our Services.  We may also ask for additional information about items and services requested and delivery and service notes, and other information you may choose to provide in order to, for example, facilitate communications among users or to monitor work orders and invoices. We may aggregate and/or anonymize your Personal Information so that you cannot be individually identified, and provide that information to our other customers, service providers, partners or other third parties, including, without limitation, to provide benchmarking data.

2\. Information We Collect Through Your Use of Our Services

When you use our Services, we may collect the following information about you:

**Transaction Information:**  We collect transaction details related to your use of our Services. This includes check-in and check-out information, dispatch information, the type of Service requested or delivered, diagnostic fees, fee changes, final fees, the date and time the service was provided, and ratings feedback.

**Financial Information:** We do not currently collect financial information, such as your payment method (valid credit card number, type, expiration date or other financial information); that information is collected and stored by our third party payment processing company (the “Payment Processor”), and use and storage of that information is governed by the Payment Processor’s applicable terms of service and privacy policy.  Presently, we use Stripe as our Payment Processor, and their privacy policy is found [here](http://stripe.com/us/privacy/).

**Location Information:**  Where you consent to such use through the permission system on your mobile operating system, we may collect precise location data about your location.  We use this location information, for example, to determine if the user is on site in a customer location.  We may also approximate your current location using your IP address. Where you have allowed the App to access location services through your mobile operating system’s permission system, we may also collect the location of your device when the App is running in the foreground or background.

**Contacts Information:**  Where you consent to such use through the permission system on your mobile operating system, we may access and store names and contact information from your address book to facilitate social interactions through our Services and for other purposes described in this Statement or at the time of consent or collection.

**Device Information:** We may collect information about the mobile device you use to access the Services. This information may include the hardware model, operating system and version, and other unique device identifiers.

**Information Collected Automatically:** Whenever you interact with our Services, we automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, “cookie” information, the page you requested, App usage, App crashes, and other system activity. 

**Cookies and Similar Technologies:** We and our service providers may use technologies like “cookies,” pixels, and local storage (like on your browser or device, which is similar to a cookie but holds more information) and identifiers (including identifiers supplied by your browser or device or by app platform companies) on our website, in our emails, and within our apps to provide you with a range of products and services. You can control cookies through your browser settings and other tools. For more information, including the types of cookies and similar technologies found on the Services, please read ServiceChannel’s ‘[Cookie Policy](https://servicechannel.info/cookie-policy)’.  Please be aware that limiting the ability of websites to set cookies, however, may worsen your overall user experience, and in some cases the Services will not work properly without the use of cookies, local storage and similar technologies.

3\. Information We Receive from Third Parties

We receive and store information from third parties that interact in some way with the Services or that provide services to us in connection with the Services. In addition, you may choose to use third party services, websites or apps that share your Personal Information, activities and/or content with ServiceChannel. Please read the privacy policy of any such service so that you understand its sharing practices.

**III. USE AND SHARING OF INFORMATION**

We neither rent nor sell your Personal Information in personally identifiable form to anyone.  However, we do use and share with third parties your Personal Information and Other Information as described in Section II and in this Section:

**Service Providers:** We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you, such as your profile information (including your address), the location of your device and other information. Unless we tell you differently, our service providers do not have any right to use the Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us.

**Customers:  **We will make information available through the Services to customers to whom you provide your services or who provide services to you, such as your photograph, profile information and other information made available to customers through the Service.  We have no control over the uses that such customers may make of information provided to them.

**Payment Processors:**  As noted above, we use a third party Payment Processor, with which we share Personal Information in order to complete transactions on the Services.  As noted above, we currently use Stripe as our Payment Processor, and their privacy policy is found [here](http://stripe.com/us/privacy/).

**Background Check Information:  **Customers may use the Services to access third-party services, including to request and obtain certain third-party reports, analyses and information related to background checks. Submitting such a request may require the provision of personally identifiable information of the applicable individuals (whether employees or contractors), such as technicians, who are the subject of the background check, including the applicable individual’s full name, e-mail address, social security number, date of birth and phone number. The provision and use of any such information is subject to the applicable terms, conditions and policies of such third-party service providers and applicable law. You are solely responsible for providing and transmitting any such information and for any information that you choose to provide to us or to third parties, or that you may authorize us to provide to third parties on your behalf, using the Services (including any consents or notices related thereto). Presently, we use Checkr, Inc. to enable you to request reports, analyses and information related to background checks, and their privacy policy is found [here](https://checkr.com/privacy-policy/).

**User Profiles and Submissions:** User profile information, including without limitation a user’s name and photograph, username, company name, phone number, email address, and postal address that such user has uploaded to the Services, may be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Services.  

**Facilitate Communications Between Users.** We enable communication between users of the Service, for example, to enable and facilitate communications between a customer and a service contractor, including to initiate a service request, to provide estimated times of arrivals, or the assessment of fees to be paid in connection with the provision of a user’s request for servicing.

**Facilitate Communications Between ServiceChannel and you.**  We may use your information to send you communications we think will be of interest to you, including information about products, services, promotions, news, and events of ServiceChannel and other companies, where permissible and according to local applicable laws; and to process contest, sweepstake, or other promotion entries and fulfill any related awards.

**Services Provision, Maintenance and Upgrades.** We use your information to provide, maintain, improve and personalize our Services, including, to send receipts, provide products and services you request (and send related information), develop new features, provide customer support to you, develop safety features, authenticate users, send product updates and administrative messages, to perform internal operations, including, for example, to prevent fraud and abuse of our Services; to troubleshoot software bugs and operational problems; to conduct data analysis, testing, and research; and to monitor and analyze usage and activity trends.  

**Business Transfers:** We may choose to buy or sell assets.  In these types of transactions, customer information is typically one of the business assets that would be transferred.  Also, if we (or our assets) are acquired, or if we go out of business, enter bankruptcy, or go through some other change of control, Personal Information would be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by third parties. 

**Protection of ServiceChannel and Others:** We reserve the right to access, read, preserve, and disclose any information that we reasonably believe is necessary to comply with law or a court order; enforce or apply our conditions of use and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or the safety of ServiceChannel, our employees, our users, or others.  This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**With Your Consent:** Except as set forth above, you will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties in personally identifiable form, and will be offered an opportunity to prevent the sharing of this information.

**Internal Operations, Analytics and Testing.** We use both Personal Information and Other Information to perform internal operations, including, for example, to prevent fraud and abuse of our Services; to troubleshoot software bugs and operational problems; to conduct analysis, testing, and research; and for monitoring and analyzing usage rates. In particular, we use Google Analytics to help us to collect and analyze certain information for the purposes discussed above. To opt-out of Google Analytics, click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

**Aggregated and/or Anonymized Data.** We may use any aggregated and/or anonymized data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information after you update or delete it for any purpose, but not in a manner that would identify you personally.  

**Advertisers.** We may use third parties to administer a limited set of ServiceChannel advertisements on third party electronic channels. No Personal Information is provided to the advertisers as part of this process, but aggregate profile information or Other Information, such as implied or inferred interests, may be used in the selection of advertising to make sure that it has relevance to the user. Some banner ads may contain embedded pixels that may write and read cookies or return session connection information that allows advertisers to better determine how many individual users have clicked on the ad banner.  We may also use advertising technologies and participate in advertising technology networks that collect Other Information from ServiceChannel and non-ServiceChannel Services, as well as from other sources, to show you ServiceChannel-related advertisements on ServiceChannel’s own and third-party websites and apps. These advertisements may be tailored to your perceived interests using retargeting and behavioral advertising technologies, a set of practices collectively referred to as “Interest Based Advertising” in this Privacy Policy.  For more information about Interest Based Advertising, including how to opt-out, visit [youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) (applicable for European users only), the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-digital-advertising) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/). You may opt out of certain Interest Based Advertising by following the instructions in the “What Rights and Choices Do I Have?” section of this Privacy Policy. Opting-out does not mean that you will stop receiving ads from ServiceChannel. It means that you still stop receiving ads from ServiceChannel that have been targeted to you based on your visits and browsing activity across websites over time.  For more information, see the “What Choices Do I Have?” section below.

**Other Information.** We may use, transfer, and disclose Other Information we collect for any purpose, except where applicable law requires otherwise. If we are required to treat Other Information as Personal Information under applicable law, then we will only use it in the same way that we are permitted to use and disclose Personal Information. ****

**IV. LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING PERSONAL INFORMATION**

The grounds on which we process your Personal Information include where you have given your consent, where it is necessary to provide you the Service, where it is in our legitimate interest. 

In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contact with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). 

If we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), this interest will normally be to operate our platform and communicating with you as necessary to provide our services to you and for our legitimate commercial interest, for instance, when responding to your queries, improving our platform, undertaking marketing, or for the purposes of detecting or preventing illegal activities.  We may have other legitimate interests and if appropriate we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are. ****

**V. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

ServiceChannel.com, Inc is a United States company and as such we process and store Personal Information and Other Information in the United States.  As a result, United States federal and state governments, courts, or law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through laws applicable in the United States. If you use the Services or submit any Personal Information to us, you acknowledge that your Personal Information will be transferred from your home country to the US which may provide for different data protection rules than in your country.

However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  These include implementing Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of personal information between our group companies, which require all group companies to protect personal information they process from the EEA in accordance with European Union data protection law. 

Our Standard Contractual Clauses can be provided on request.

**VI. WHAT RIGHTS AND CHOICES DO I HAVE?**

1. User Account Information

You may correct your account information at any time by updating your account through the Services.

If you wish to cancel your account, please email us at [support@servicechannel.com](mailto:support@servicechannel.com). Please note that some information may remain in our records after your deletion of such information from your account. We may use any aggregated data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information after you update or delete it, but not in a manner that would identify you personally.  

ServiceChannel will comply with individual’s requests regarding access, correction, and/or deletion of the personal data it stores in accordance with applicable law.

**Your European Privacy Rights**

Under European data protection and privacy laws, if applicable the following rights are available to you subject to conditions and exemptions; 

  * If you wish to access, correct, update or request deletion of your personal information, you can do so at any time by contacting us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below. 
  * In addition, you can object to processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below.
  * You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications we send you at any time.  You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing e-mails we send you.  To opt-out of other forms of marketing (such as postal marketing or telemarketing), then please contact us using the contact details provided under the “How to contact us” heading below.
  * Similarly, if we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time.  Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information.  For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. 

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws. ****

**VII. DATA RETENTION**

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements). 

We will hold Personal Information about you after you cancel your account for no more than two (2) years after the applicable account is deleted.  

**Your California Privacy Rights**

Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us once a year for a notice identifying the categories of personal customer information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for their own direct marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to the following address: ServiceChannel.com, Inc., 18 East 16th Street, 2nd Floor, New York, NY 10003. 

2\. Interest Based Advertising

As discussed above, we may partner with third parties to provide Interest Based Advertising. For information about how to opt out of receiving interest-based advertisements, or to learn more about interest-based advertising in general and to access the opt-outs of other online advertising companies, visit Your Online Choices at [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) (applicable for European subjects only), the Network Advertising Initiative at [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed) or the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) at [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) or, for interest-based advertising in apps, by using the DAA’s “AppChoices” application available at [http://http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices/). By opting out, you may still receive ads from ServiceChannel, but you still stop receiving ads from ServiceChannel that have been targeted to you based on your visits and browsing activity across websites over time.

Also, certain versions of the iOS operating system permit you to “Limit Ad Tracking” in the system settings and certain versions of the Android operating system allow you to “Opt out of Interest-Based Ads” in the system settings.

At this time we do not honor web browser Do Not Track (“DNT”) signals or similar mechanisms.

**VIII. MARKETING AND EMAIL COMMUNICATION**

By providing your email address to us, you acknowledge that you will  receive emails from us, where permitted by law. We may use email to communicate with you, to send information that you have requested or to send information about other products or services developed or provided by us or our partners. If you do not want to receive commercial email or other mail from us, you may unsubscribe using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of an email you receive. Please note that if you do not want to receive legal notices from us, such as notices regarding this Privacy Policy, those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are responsible for reviewing such legal notices for changes. We may receive a confirmation when you open an email from ServiceChannel if your computer supports this type of program. ServiceChannel uses this confirmation to help us make emails more interesting and helpful and to improve our service. ****

**IX. SECURITY**

ServiceChannel uses commercially reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your Personal Information against loss or unauthorized access, use, modification, or deletion. However, no security program is foolproof, and thus we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your Personal Information or Other Information. ****

**X. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time.  Use of information we collect now is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is used.  If we make changes in the way we use Personal Information, we will notify you by posting an announcement on our Website or sending you a message. You are bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when you use the Services after such changes have been first posted. ****

**XI. CONTACT US**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy, please send us a message to[ support@servicechannel.com](mailto:support@servicechannel.com), and we will try to resolve your concerns.

Last Updated May 17, 2018; __ Effective Date: June 15, 2018
